RICKY GARCIA

385.416.7996 | rq3646@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

PERFORMANCE SUMMARY

Front-End Development & Refactoring - Refactored attachments section of Vyne Trellis, replacing Kendo with Ant Design and introducing TypeScript for enhanced type safety. By fixing existing and undiscovered bugs, increased application speed, stability, and user satisfaction. Transformed monolithic codebase into smaller, isolated components, resulting in improved code readability, testability, and overall usability.

Flow Engineering & Product Development - Engineered Purple's pre-checkout cart new checkout flow, increasing add-on products sales from customers and improving checkout completion rates. Redesigned flow, delegated tasks, communicated effectively with product and marketing teams, and collaborated closely with QA to ensure seamless and error-free checkout experience.

Product Optimization & UX/UI Design - Navigated challenge of Purple's impromptu promotion sale, leading to impressive increase in sales by \$1M+ compared to baseline sales. Collaborated closely with the team to efficiently divide tasks and successfully implemented new strategies to optimize the promotion sale process.

Front-End Development

Team Collaboration

Version Control

Agile and Continuous Improvement

Business Process Optimization

Cloud Solutions & Delivery

Product Design & Launch Initiatives

Mentoring & Coaching Developers

Project Management

Workflow Management

Data & Analytics

IT Infrastructure & Operations

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

B.S., Economics, Idaho State University, City, State

AWS Certified DevOps - Professional AWS Certified Developer - Associate

TECH STACKS

DevOps

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, SCSS, CSS, C#

Web Frameworks React, Vue, Angular, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Material UI, ¡Query, .Net Core

Cloud Technologies AWS, S3, CloudFront, CloudWatch, Cloudformation, Lambda, Route 53, IAM, AWS Certificate

Manager, Elastic Beanstalk, SES, SNS, CloudTrail Azure Pipeline, Github Actions, GitLab Workflows

Software Atlassian – JIRA, Confluence; GitLab, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Bash,

Command line, Google Developer Tools, Adobe - Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator, XD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 V_{YNE} **D**ENTAL, Indianapolis, Indiana

Senior Software Engineer, February 2022 – March 2023

- Developed new features and enhanced existing ones for Vyne Trellis, dental billing software hub, using React, TypeScript, Ant Design, Azure, and AWS
- Reduced technical debt by identifying areas for improvement, creating work tickets, and refactoring legacy JavaScript code to TypeScript
- Improved codebase maintainability by separating spaghetti code into modular components and promoting clean coding practices
- Mentored junior developers, cultivating collaborative and supportive learning environment to foster professional growth

Purple, Lehi, Utah

Senior Software Engineer, February 2021 – February 2022

 Managed promotions and sales for Purple products, driving revenue growth during high-traffic periods like Black Friday and Christmas on live customer-facing website

- Enhanced developer and user experience by introducing new features and redesigning pre-checkout cart to improve UX and increase sales
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including Promotions, Design, Product, QA, and Project Management, in agile environment, participating in daily standups, sprints, and handoffs for seamless coordination
- Utilized JavaScript, SCSS, Vue.js, and Craft CMS to develop and implement front-end content for both new and existing products, ensuring a compelling and engaging user experience
- Facilitated training sessions on CMS and Website utilization by leading engaging seminars and lunch and learn sessions, empowering team of 30-40 software members to master content management and leverage it effectively

CARDWORKS, South Jordan, Utah Software Engineer, September 2019 – February 2021

- Enhanced internal ticketing system, a critical application for tracking activity and optimizing workflows for Data Analysts, by implementing new features and improving front-end interface
- Optimized performance of site by conducting code reviews, identifying and resolving bottlenecks, and implementing best practices for efficient data processing
- Fostered close collaboration with Data Analyst team to understand business needs and requirements, resulting in continuous improvements to application that aligned with workflows
- Leveraged technologies including Angular, .Net, C#, TypeScript, MSSQL Server, and SCSS to develop and deliver a robust, scalable, and efficient solution for internal ticketing system

Melaleuca: The Wellness Company, Idaho Falls, Idaho Front End Developer II, December 2018 – June 2019

- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to create and deliver captivating user experiences for product pages and microsites, ensuring exceptional user engagement and satisfaction
- Worked collaboratively in an agile environment, partnering with backend developers to develop comprehensive solutions that met business requirements and delivered seamless end-to-end functionality
- Successfully developed and launched new features while maintaining existing codebases, ensuring high-quality and reliable software performance
- Utilized C#, SCSS, Agile Methodologies, JavaScript, React.js, and HTML to write clean, efficient, and maintainable code, resulting in delivery of high-quality front-end solutions

Micron Technology, Meridian, Idaho Front End Web Producer, June 2018 – December 2018

- Created visually captivating designs for Micron Consumer Products Group's domestic, regional, and international sites, resulting in engaging and visually appealing user experiences
- Demonstrated problem-solving skills by identifying and addressing site issues within tight time constraints, collaborating with multiple departments and time zones to develop effective solutions and achieve desired outcomes
- Proficiently operated Content Management Systems and eCommerce tools to ensure efficient site production and content updates
- Leveraged Adobe Experience Manager (AEM), Jira, Agile Methodologies, JavaScript, and Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to deliver high-quality front-end work, ensuring seamless functionality and visually appealing designs

RS&I, Idaho Falls, Idaho Web Designer & Developer, February 2017– July 2018

- Spearheaded redesign of customer-facing website and HubSpot blog, demonstrating strong leadership in web design and development to achieve visually stunning and user-friendly online presence
- Enhanced website performance by creating custom solutions, including landing pages, resulting in improved loading times and user engagement
- Successfully restructured the web leads funnel, implementing strategic changes to improve lead generation and enhance the overall customer experience, resulting in increased lead conversion and higher customer satisfaction